Erica Goodwin UI/UX Designer / Frontend Developer

Email: ericagoodwin90@gmail.com

Phone: 0272536240

Portfolio: https://ejgoodwin.github.io/portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/ejgoodwin

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/erica-goodwin-4b6b64112/

Skills / Experience

- UI/UX design
- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Responsive design
- HTML, CSS3, SASS, BEM
- · JavaScript, ¡Query, React.js
- · WordPress (custom template development), PHP
- Git

Personal Profile

I have been involved in the entire lifecycle of websites: design, converting designs to functional sites (HTML, CSS, jQuery, PHP), testing and deployment. Throughout the process I liaise with clients, account managers and designers to assess and implement the best solutions to problems. All sites are fully responsive and cross browser tested.

I am particularly interested in animations and micro-interactions, as they bring so much to the user's experience but are often so subtle they go unnoticed. My coding skills allow me to quickly build static prototypes to test the designs, and it is great to see your creation come to life.

I find knowledge of coding helps me to design better interfaces, and design skills help while coding interactions or states that have not been explicitly designed.

Work Experience

Designer / UI Frontend Developer - Straker Translations (Auckland, NZ), Aug 2019 - present (Contract)

- Redesigning UI of web applications
- · Creating style guide and pattern library to ensure consistency for design and development

Web Design and Frontend Development - ARA (Sydney, Aus), Nov 2018 - May 2019 (6 month contract)

- Building and maintaining websites for ARA companies and internal projects
- Working with React.is and WordPress building custom themes from scratch
- Create full website designs to be approved by the client
- Build fully functional, responsive websites from designs

UI Developer - 4Mation Technologies (Sydney, Aus), Aug 2018 - Nov 2018 (Contract)

- Develop interfaces for large-scale applications using HTML, SASS and Javascript
- Utilise and add to pattern libraries to create modular and scaleable code

Web Designer - Adtrak (Nottingham, UK), Jan 2017 - June 2018

- Design and code websites using WordPress CMS building custom themes from scratch
- Work closely with clients, utilising InVision to enable the client to view and comment on the design
- Liaise with other departments and clients to deliver sites that are functional and perform well
- Work through the entire process from design to code to deployment
- Experience in setting sites live, transferring domains, handling databases

Academic Support Worker - The Learning Support Centre (Leicester, UK), 03/2015 - 03/2016

- Supported students with learning difficulties and/or disabilities in academic situations, including lectures and exams
- Provided transcription work for visually impaired
- Built trusting, professional relationships and responded to needs of clients/service users

Education

York University 2019 - present MSc Computer Science (online)

De Montfort University 2013 - 2016 BA(Hons) Fine Art: 2:2 (59%)

De Montfort University 2012 - 2013 Art and Design (Foundation Studies) BTEC Diploma

Leicester College 2011 - 2012 Foundation Degree in Artistic Makeup and Special Effects

Queen Elizabeth II College

A Levels: Art - B; Photography - D

AS Levels: Art - A; English Literature - D; Photography - C; Graphics - D

Sir Jonathon North Community College GCSE Grades - 5As, 3Bs, 1C, 1D

Interests

In my spare time I am expanding my knowledge in development by studying computer science, which is giving me great fundamental programming skills. I enjoy the logic and problem solving aspects of coding, and also the way it allows me to continuously learn and push myself to discover and build new skills.

If I'm not studying, I like to venture out to the countryside and explore the wilderness.